起来  豪斯
Get up, House.
一定有什么误会
Must be some mistake.
我特别要求过
I specifically requested my wakeup startle
三小时后再吓醒我
three hours from now.
有大人物来看你
Some VIP visitor.
是你原来医院的院长
Dean of Medicine from your old hospital.
我梦见过这一幕啊
I've had dreams about this.
我就当现在又在做梦了
I'm going to assume this is another one.
快起来
Get up.
谁来看我  我都可以拒绝接见
I can refuse to see any visitor I want.
告诉院长  我不想见她
Tell the dean that I don't want to see her.
他说你会这么说的
He said you'd say that.
男的他吗
He?
医院那边是怎么雇人的啊
What's the hiring policy over there?
全雇混蛋吗
All ass based?
我能把你弄出去
I can get you out of here.
除非太阳打西边出来
Not unless that file has a file in it.
这是法官的判决  可以立即释放你
Judge's order for your immediate release.
两个月前我被判增加八个月的服刑期
I had eight months added to my sentence two months ago.
挺好算的吧
The math is pretty basic.
我们遇到麻烦了
We have a crisis,
对你来说倒是个好消息
which is good news for you.
你今晚就可以被有条件释放
You're out tonight on conditional parole.
条件就是你受我雇佣
The condition being that you're employed by me
继续留在医院
at PPTH.
不用了  谢谢
No, thanks.
你认为对我们俩来说
You think it's a good idea for me to go right back
让我回到过去的生活是个好主意吗
to my old life for either of us?
你的病人是一对恒温保存箱里的肺
Your patient is two lungs in a box,
而且只能存活12小时
and it only has 12 hours left.
没有脉搏  没有身体
No pulse, no body,
无法回答问题
no ability to answer questions.
这位病人非你莫属
It's your perfect patient.
我确实为那间房掏了一整周的钱  但
I did pay for the room for the whole week, but...
器官捐献者是名十八岁的学生
Donor's an 18-year-old college kid
从霍夫斯特拉大学回来
back from Hosftra
和他的朋友一起参加返校节派对
goes to a homecoming party with his buddies,
骑上摩托  结果成了名捐献器官者
hops on his motorcycle, ends up an organ donor.
在急诊室里心脏停止跳动
Asystole in the E.R.
没有脉搏
No pulse.
血液循环停止
No blood circulating.
他的心脏  肝  肾全坏了
His heart, liver, kidneys were all toast.
外科医生都把接受者送上手术台了
Surgeons had the recipient on the table
才发现这对肺出现呼吸道阻力上升现象
when they realized the lungs had increased airway resistance.
他们只能先把她缝合
The team closed her up,
让肺进入"休眠状态"
put the lungs in suspended animation.
这样争取到24小时来解决问题
Buys 24 hours to fix it,
现在时间已经过了一半
12 of which have passed.
我们还是不清楚问题出在哪里
We still have no clue what's wrong.
画挺漂亮
Nice painting.
蓝色和绿色
Blues and greens.
能安抚情绪  又带点治愈色彩
Calming, but with a hint of nurturing.
和遭罪与死亡真是天差地别
Totally opposite of the stance of suffering and death.
我的病人在哪里
Where's my patient?
我们需要不说话
We need to not talk.
在重症监护室的隔离房间
ICU isolation room.
移植手术人员会在那里等你
The transplant team will meet you there
给你说明过去两个小时的情况
with updates from the past two hours.
太好了  拿着这个
Great. Take this.
不如放到你的办公室吧
How about you drop it in your office?
看到你院长的头衔
I completely understand
我完全能理解你
and almost respect your desire
想当院长的心
to appear to be Dean of Medicine,
都快到要敬佩你的地步了
given that your title is Dean of Medicine.
另外...
On the other hand...
真的假的啊
seriously?
丑话说在前
Get this straight.
你再犯法  就回监狱去
You break the law, you go back to jail.
再多骗维柯丁  也回监狱去
Scam extra Vicodin, back to jail.
藐视我的权威  让医院难堪
Flout my authority, make the hospital look bad,
还是回监狱去
back to jail.
你是我的了
I own you.
好的  主人
Yes, massa.
看  这就对了
See, that would be an example.
卡迪什么时候走的
When did Cuddy leave?
你闯祸第二天  她就辞职了
She gave her notice the day after your incident.
接受了...
Took a job--
不需要这么详细
Don't need the details.
整形外科需要更大的空间
Ortho needed more space.
你办公室在这边
You're this way.
我的东西呢
Where's my stuff?
不知道
No idea.
那我的团队呢
What about my team?
可悲
Pathetic.
你一见我就说
The first thing you said to me
你不想回到过去的生活
was you don't want your old environment.
三句话过后就问"我的旧家伙哪里去了"
The fourth thing you said was, "Where's my old environment?"
一年了
It's been a year.
陶博  奇斯  十三都有新的事业了
Taub, Chase, Thirteen all moved on.
就是这样
The world does that sometimes.
才不是呢
No, it doesn't.
这是你的新办公室
Here's your new office,
那是你新的团队
and there's your new team.
你好
Hi.
我对别科挑剩下的人没兴趣
I'm not interested in another department's sloppy seconds.
我不是挑剩下的
I'm not sloppy seconds.
凌晨三点
It's 3:00 a.m.,
如果是福曼打电话把你从家里叫来的
if Foreman had called you in from home,
你就不会穿着熨好的衣服
you wouldn't have pressed clothes,
头发整齐  还化好了妆
coiffed hair, and makeup,
说明你本来就在医院
which means you were already here in the hospital.
对  我今天本该在神经科值班
Yes, I was on call for Neurology.
如果那是真话  你现在就该在工作
Well, if that were true, you'd be working right now
就没时间帮我的忙了
and unavailable to help,
也就是说你是在医院瞎转
which means that you're hanging out in the hospital
假装在工作
pretending to work,
说明你不仅仅是被拒了
which means you're not just a reject.
还是个胆小的被拒者
You're a cowardly reject
更不想让别人知道这事
who was trying to hide her rejectedness from someone.
我没有被拒
I am not a reject.
那就回神经科去
Then go back to Neurology.
不行
I can't.
我打了我的主治医生
I punched my attending.
我们最合理的猜想是
ARDS secondary to trauma
由外伤引起的急性呼吸窘迫综合征
is our leading hypothesis.
吸入氧浓度是93%
FiO2 is 93%--
进监狱喽
Prison!
抱歉
Sorry.
我猜我听到了大家的"心声"
I thought I heard everyone else think that.
你们都知道  我进了监狱
I was in prison, you see.
那是很久以前的事了  但显然你们都很好奇
It was a long time ago, but still you're curious.
从没被暴过
Never was raped.
没被强暴过
Not raped-raped.
好吧  被强抢过  但没在被强抢后被暴过
Well, raped-raped, but not raped-raped-raped.
好了  我把你们想知道的都告诉你们了
Well, now that we've got that completely behind us.
抱歉  豪斯医生  欢迎回来
Sorry, Dr. House, welcome back.
有蛋糕吗
Is there cake?
肺泡内有粒细胞渗出吗
Any alveolar exudate?
没有
No.
肺部没有水肿
Lungs are dry.
那这就不是急性呼吸窘迫综合征
Well, then it's not ARDS.
现在是秋天  蜱传播疾病的高发期
It's the autumn. It's tick-borne disease season.
这是嗜吞噬细胞无形体所致的支气管炎
Ehrlichiosis causing bronchiolitis.
你们应该感谢我没把"白痴"说出口
You'll appreciate that I left the "Idiots" subtextual.
血液涂片显示正常  我们这群"白痴"
Blood smear was clear, and we "Idiots" treated
使用了广谱抗生素进行治疗
with broad spectrum antibiotics.
-那是吸食了可卡因  -但毒理检验没有异常
- Cocaine. - Tox screen was clean.
死人不用小便
Dead men don't pee.
毒理检验是检测小便里的代谢物
Tox screen tests for metabolites in the urine.
可卡因不会流经肺部
Coke never got past the lungs.
这也能解释摩托车事故的发生原因
Also explains the motorcycle crash.
一群白痴
Idiots.
准备开始治疗吧
Let's get the lungs on treatment.
真是好主意
Great idea.
除非你想错了
Unless you're wrong.
我说的"你"是指我自己
And by you, I mean me.
这项治疗会让肺部烧出窟窿来
Then this treatment will burn holes in the lungs.
我又要说你们是"白痴"了  但这一次
I'd call you idiots again, but at this point
我开始怀疑你们压根不知道
I'm starting to doubt whether you understand
我为什么用这个词
what I mean by the word.
加藤
Kato.
去备车  在门口等我
Get Black Beauty and meet me out front.
我们要去找找这倒霉孩子藏匿的毒品
We're gonna find the dead kid's stash.
既然这名18岁的捐赠人
Since an 18-year-old with organ donor
在卡上显示为非癌症病人
on his license is not a cancer patient,
我猜测这位受赠者
I'm figuring the recipient is a lifetime member
会是威尔森关怀太多俱乐部的终身会员吧
of the Wilson cares too much club.
推理真是精彩
Excellent deduction.
你才是帮我出狱的人
You're the reason I'm out of the big house.
但这还不够弥补你从不来探...
Doesn't quite make up for never visiting--
把你弄回来是福曼的主意
Springing you was Foreman's idea.
我一直没同意  直到辛普森失败了三次
I wasn't convinced until Simpson failed three times.
这只能说明同一件事
It amounts to the same thing.
你想让我回来
You wanted me back.
看见没  我就知道你会曲解我的话
See, I knew you'd over-interpret it.
反应过分强烈激动
Strong, emotional reaction.
我猜这就是终身会员对你的影响
I guess that's what a lifetime membership gets you.
-你的膝盖怎样了  -痊愈了
- How's your wrist?  - Healed.
谢谢关心
Thank you.
我错了
I was wrong.
我坐了牢  为自己的行为付出了代价
I went to prison. I paid the price.
你都接受改造了
You're a changed man.
我是说我错了  没说我变了
I said I was wrong. I didn't say I changed.
我没变
I haven't.
-你也没变...  -随便你怎么说
- Neither have you--  - Analyze it however you like.
我们不再是朋友了
We're not friends anymore.
哪里不舒服吗
What can I do?
我的胸口
My chest.
绞痛又发作了
Angina's back.
加点硝化甘油能缓解疼痛
Upping the nitro should knock it back down.
刚才我和姐姐在讨论
Sis and I were talking,
我们一共在医院住过几夜
trying to figure out how many hospital sleepovers we've had.
就是从2001年
It definitely started with the
我接受乳房切除术开始的
great mastectomy of 2001.
老天  我真想念我的乳房
God, I miss my boobs.
绝对的"峰"满动人
They were spectacular.
还有希望另找一位捐赠者吗
Is there a chance of locating another donor?
不太可能
It's unlikely.
尤其是
Especially since,
她的肺气肿恶化  需要一对肺
with the extent of the emphysema, she needs a double lung.
还在疼吗
How are you doing?
已经好些了
Better already.
很高兴那药起作用了  我想让你给我带一整瓶来
It's a good thing that worked. I was gonna make you bring me a bottle.
老妹  打起精神来
Oh, lighten up, Sis.
至少你可以在听这位即将死去的女士
You know, the least you could do
讲笑话的时候笑一笑
is laugh at a dying lady's jokes.
你那会喝酒一点意思都没有
Your drinking wasn't funny then,
现在的笑话也一点不好笑
and it's not funny now.
因为你不会死
Because you're not dying.
医院请来了一位顾问医师
The hospital brought in a consultant
来解决捐赠者肺部出现的问题
to work on the lungs.
你认识他吗  他的水平怎么样
Do you know him? Is he--is he good?
他是位很出色的医生
He is an excellent doctor.
我们或许不该像这样冒然拜访
We probably shouldn't be turning up unannounced like this.
他们的儿子刚刚过世
Their son just died.
乐观点...他们或许刚从哭泣中醒来
Bright side--they're probably up weeping.
我们都袭击过自己的上司
Hey, we both assaulted our bosses.
这点上咱俩可真是志同道合
It's like we're twins.
-我真的...  -好吧我先说  我的上司抛弃了我
- I really-- - OK, I'll go first. My boss dumped me.
你呢  被叫做他的瓷娃娃吗
And yours what? Called you his China doll?
嘲笑你在曼哈顿买的便宜货吗
Joked about what a crappy deal you got for Manhattan?
以为你是男人吗
Assumed you have a huge penis?
我还不知道你是什么类型的人
I have no idea what flavor you are,
所以我做了各种猜测
so I thought I'd just cover the spread.
我妈妈是菲律宾人  爸爸是韩国人
My mom's Filipino, dad's Korean,
我的上司从背后抓住了我
and my boss grabbed my behind.
抓住后面的什么
Behind what?
哦...抓住了你的臀部
Oh, yeah, your--grabbed your tushy.
所以你现在假装在值班
So now you're pretending to be on call
这样你那位过度敏感的男友
so that your overly protective boyfriend
就不会发现你被人调戏了
won't find out that you got groped.
我没有男朋友
I don't have a boyfriend.
我这么做是因为我的父母
It's my parents.
如果他们发现我打了上司  会觉得受到了羞辱
If they found out what I've done, they'd be mortified.
你的父母知道你的值班时间吗
Your parents know your call schedule?
我和他们住在一起
I live with them.
好吧
Right.
我没有问题了
No issues there.
我都已经说了  我的儿子没有吸食过可卡因
I told you my son didn't do cocaine.
瘾君子可不会说实话
Druggies are not known for their honesty.
相信我这句话
Trust me on this one.
怀勒斯先生  我相信您说的话
Mr.Weathers, I am sure you're right,
但我们不能有半点疏忽
but we need to be thorough.
你儿子吸食过大麻吗
Did your son ever smoke marijuana?
他是个运动员
He was an athlete.
很注意保持健康
Took real good care of himself.
你别毛手毛脚的
Hey, take it easy.
-那些都是史蒂夫的宝贝  -对不起
- Steve loved all that. - Sorry.
我们赶时间
But we're on a clock.
我觉得他要赶我们走了
I think he's about to throw us out.
不会的
Nope.
他儿子死了
His son is dead.
他死得是否有意义
The only way that has any meaning
就看我们能否救活那两页肺并完成移植
is if we fix the lungs and transplant them.
我们怎么惹他都没关系
It doesn't matter how much we piss him off
只要我们能找到证据
as long as we find something.
所以你过去
So go back there,
惹毛他
piss him off
问点线索出来
and find something.
你认识那些和你儿子
Do you know any of the kids
一起参加聚会的孩子吗
at the party with your son?
就是些他高中的朋友
Bunch of his high school buddies.
他们开始打牌
They got ready a poker.
最后决定在布兰登·布鲁姆家
Decided to have an all-night game
的地下室玩通宵
in Brandon Broome's basement.
我知道我们赶时间
I understand that we're in a hurry.
他可能不会赶我们走
He's probably not gonna throw us out.
但他真应该那么做
But maybe he should.
相片里你儿子都不戴眼镜
Your son isn't wearing glasses in any of these pictures.
他几周前才配的
He just got them a couple of weeks ago.
是因为他头疼吗
Because he was having headaches?
先回答问题再去开门
Answer the question before answering the door.
是的  他是头疼
Yeah, he was.
你是对的
You were right.
你儿子没吸毒
He was not doing cocaine.
他生了脑瘤
He had a brain tumor.
别去开了  是找我的
Don't bother. It's for me.
看来
Turns out
他们还是会监视这些监视器的
they monitor these monitors.
谢谢你  警官
Thank you officer.
我以为戴脚链是为了好看
I thought the bracelet was decorative.
我婶婶也有个一样的
My aunt has one just like it.
-等一下  -允许你待医院
- Wait a minute. - You're allowed to be at the hospital.
允许你回家
You're allowed to go home.
之前和你说清楚的
That was made clear.
那男孩的家就在我回家的路上
Dead kid's house was on the way to my apartment.
我可能迷了两次路
Assuming I got lost, twice.
我办公室里的那些顾问多等一分钟
Those consultants in my office are only costing the hospital
就要多花我们一百美元
100 bucks every minute I keep them waiting.
你就不能告诉我你在干什么吗
Why didn't you just tell me what you were doing?
我知道你忙着装你的大人物呢
I knew you were very busy being vaguely important.
我就应该向警方澄清的
I might have cleared it with the cops.
就是"应该"这词害惨得我
Yeah, it's the word "might" that bumps me.
下次我会先和你说的
I'll run it by you next time.
豪斯
House.
董事会不太赞成
Getting you out of jail
把你保释出狱
was not a popular decision with the board.
我需要你解决这病例
I need you to solve this,
也需要你在完成任务的同时
and I need you to do it without making me
别让我太难堪
look like I can't control you.
这对你我都有好处
For both our sakes.
纪律监察听证会乐趣无穷啊
Disciplinarian hearing should be fun.
之后就会在你档案里留下永远的污点
And the subsequent lingering black mark on your record.
我不担心
I'm not worried.
我们得把尸体送去做磁共振
We have to wheel this out to the MRI.
还是不要打开袋子为妙
We should probably leave the body in the bag.
他手臂上有个肿块
There's a mass in the arm.
分析下这块肿瘤要比全身检查快
Analyzing part of this tumor is gonna be quicker than a scan.
那么你准备去哪里工作
So where's the next job?
你很看重人们对你的看法
You worry about what people think of you,
所以你衣着整齐  发型清爽
thus the carefully maintained hair, clothes
而且还对父母有所隐瞒
and parental secrets.
你之所以不担心听证会
The only way that you don't worry about this hearing
只有可能是你认为根本就不会有听证
is if you don't think there's gonna be one.
这样的话  唯一的可能
The only way that happens
就是你离开普林斯顿普雷斯波罗教学医院
is you leave Princeton Plainsboro.
我昨天和芝加哥医院进行了一次视频面试
I had a video interview with Chicago yesterday.
还不错
It went well.
我押他得的是横纹肌瘤
My money's on rhabdomyosarcoma.
芝加哥可是个好地方
Chicago has a great program.
不过你太蠢了
And you're a dumbass.
背井离乡算是悠久的传统了
Running away from home is a time-honored tradition,
不过你这么做不是为了逃离父母
but you're not doing it to flee your parents.
却是为了保护他们
You're doing it to protect them.
你这么做
That's an insult
让那些尚未成年的站街女情何以堪啊
to everything teen prostitutes have worked for.
你也该长大了  和他们说清楚
Time to grow up and come clean.
你说得对
You're right.
我就该开车
I should just drive my car
撞进客厅去告诉他们
into a living room to tell them.
最后是不是他偷了那个热狗摊
Didn't it turn out that he'd stolen the hot dog cart?
不对  他那是借用
No, borrowed.
鲍比对于这点很坚持的
Bobby was very insistent on that point.
看来你感觉好点了
Seems like someone's feeling better.
胸口不痛了
No more chest pain.
鲍比这个名字好久不听见了
I haven't heard the name Bobby in a long time.
他最近如何啊
How's he doing these days?
我不清楚  我们没联系过
I don't know. We're not in touch.
你就别装了  你算舒了口气吧
And don't even pretend like you're not relieved.
你压根儿就看他不爽
You never liked him.
鲍比是个很有趣的家伙
Bobby is an incredibly fun, great guy.
就是影响不太好
Just not a great influence.
要我说  他就是个酒鬼
I would have gone with "Colossal drunk."
我还想着要暗示呢  没错  就是个酒鬼
I was gonna leave that implied, but, yes, colossal drunk.
酒鬼怎么了  小夫妻俩就不能有点共同爱好吗
What? It's good for a couple to share a hobby.
你的导尿袋是空的
Your catheter bag is empty,
你已经输了两百毫升的液了
Despite taking in 200 ccs of fluids.
我得把硝化甘油关了
I'm gonna have to dial back the nitro.
她胸口是不是又要疼了
Won't her chest pain come back?
没办法
We don't have any choice.
硝化甘油阻断了向肾脏的供血
The nitro is dropping the blood flow to your kidneys.
现在肾脏开始衰竭了
They're shutting down.
*咫尺  或是天涯*
*Near, far*
*无论你在哪里*
*Wherever you are*
*我相信*
*I believe*
这歌唱得就是我们俩啊
This is so our song.
我的病人时日不多了
My patient is running out of time.
爷不担心
Not worried.
咱说话这会儿  我的"团队"正在确诊
My team is confirming the diagnosis as we speak.
*你打开了门*
*You open the door*
我想通情达理一些
I want to be understanding.
这是你回来第一天
It's your first day back--
看  想要移情于我
See? I smell empathy.
想想那些美好的回忆吧
Just remember all the good times.
比如上次我给你一根项链
Like when I gave you that necklace
结果你扔海里了
that you just dumped in the ocean.
当时你想什么呢
What were you thinking?
豪斯  我没有忘记我们的友情
House, I haven't forgotten our friendship.
但所有好的回忆  总伴着一堆坏的
For every good memory, there's a slew of bad ones.
-进来  -进来
- Come in. - Come in.
不是副癌综合征
Paraneoplastic syndrome's out.
肺捐献者没有癌症
The lung donor didn't have cancer.
这话怎么不跟我在他手臂里找到的肿瘤说去
Tell that to the tumor that I found in his arm.
那不是肿瘤
That mass wasn't a tumor.
是凝固的血浆
It was coagulated plasma.
急救时输了很多血浆
E.R. pumped him full of it.
静脉注射渗进了他的手臂肌肉
I.V. leaked into his arm.
我还做了全身核磁共振
I even did a complete MRI.
没有癌细胞
No cancer anywhere.
什么都没有发现
We've got nothing.
就算它不是肿瘤
Just 'cause it wasn't a tumor
不表示这和肺无关
doesn't mean it didn't mess with the lungs.
血浆内某种物质引起了肺部的问题
They're reacting to something in the plasma.
但每一单位的血浆
But every unit of plasma
可能来自25个捐献者
can have up to 25 contributing donors.
必须追查他们所有人
We need to track down all of them.
总之
Still.
这比一千多号人
It's not as bad as a thousand people
跟着巨轮一起葬身海底要好
going down in a gigantic boat, right?
我心依旧
My heart will go on.
不  你不能离开医院
No, you can't leave the hospital.
我们的肺捐献者体内
25 donors contributed to the plasma
有25个人的血浆
that the lung donor got.
我的"团队"没法在六小时内
My team cannot track down and interview them all
走访调查所有人
in six hours.
我对你向警察作出担保
I vouch for you to the cops.
你就爱在是否违反假释上绕弯
You take some parole-violating detour
想着法子出去庆祝你重获自由  当然
celebrating your freedom, justified, of course,
你总能找到和病例有着诡异联系的正当理由
by some absurd theory connecting it to the case.
你叫我问你的
You asked me to ask you.
是为了享受拒绝的快感吗
Was that just so you'd enjoy saying no?
我不相信你  豪斯  我不能
I don't trust you, House. I can't.
实际上你必须相信
Actually you have to.
出了医院的门  我就完全不能相信你了
Not absolutely. Not outside the walls of this hospital.
行  那就给我一个
Fine, then give me a team I don't have
实实在在的团队
to put in quotation marks.
调用已经参与这件病例的人
Use the people already on the case.
给我奇斯  陶博  十三
Give me Chase, Taub, Thirteen.
我们请不起他们
We don't have the money to pay them.
对
Oh, yeah.
钱都用在装修上了  我理解
It went to interior designers, I understand.
朴克能帮你  是因为神经科会付她工资
You only have Park because she's on neurology's tab.
你赚的是最低工资
You are making minimum wage.
是吗
I am?
出去吧  谢谢
Get out of my office, please.
有什么发现
What do you got?
三号在献血之前
Number three went to a baseball game
去看过棒球比赛
the day before he donated.
无聊又不能传染
Boredom is not transmissible.
他吃了一袋花生
He ate a bag of peanuts,
可能是花生所含的蛋白质
and peanut proteins would be.
如果我们的捐献者过敏
If our donor had an allergy,
就可以解释肺部的症状
it could explain the lungs.
很好
Nice.
-什么  -没什么
- What? - Nothing.
别这样
Don't start that.
怎么样
Start what?
我很享受我们的对话
I'm enjoying our conversation.
唱双簧
The repartee.
我没跟你唱双簧
There was no repartee.
这就叫唱双簧
That was repartee.
我做这些不是为了你
I'm not doing this for you.
而是为了我的病人
I'm doing it to help my patient.
-只是很高兴听到你的声音  -挂了
- It's just good to hear your voice.  - Goodbye.
那是我的白板
That's my whiteboard.
我要用
I need it.
反正他对怎么拆石膏
And he really doesn't care
不怎么感兴趣
how the cast comes off.
福曼医生警告过我们
Dr. Foreman warned us
说你会来捣乱
that you'd try something.
如果你真来了  让我给他打电话
Told me to call him if you did.
我很乐意这么做
I'd like to do that.
我出去接
I'll take this outside.
说吧
Yeah.
六号献血者去过泰国
Donor six traveled to Thailand
呵叻附近
around Khorat.
那里流行过登革热
Region was endemic with Dengue Fever.
好
Good.
-说  -酒精
- Yeah. - Alcohol.
要影响到血浆
He had to be pretty drunk
可得酩酊大醉才行
for it to affect a pool of plasma.
他们总有办法喝成这样
These guys have got that covered.
急性酒精摄入可能引起
Acute ETOH ingestion could have--
看着点  他们又没伤害谁
Hey, paint around them! They're not hurting anyone.
谁在刷油漆
Who's painting?
工作人员刚开始刷
The crew's just starting.
油漆气体不会导致污染
Paint fumes didn't cause contamination.
但也许旧油漆会
But maybe the old paint did.
他们把旧漆刮掉
They scraped off the underpass,
可能是因为它含有
probably because it contains...
铅
Lead.
胸口又痛了吗
Chest pain back?
这次更痛了
It's worse this time.
有没有办法缓解
Is there any way to take the edge off?
我们还在对肺做检查
We're still working on the lungs.
应该很快有结果了
We should know soon.
很快就好
Soon is good.
螯合物疗怎么样了
How's the chelation going?
20分钟前月亮神父刚开始做
Reverend Moon started it about 20 minutes ago.
你在查血浆捐献者的时候
You missed lunch tracking down
没吃午餐
the plasma donors.
帮你买了千层肉三明治
Got you a reuben from the cafeteria.
谢了
Thanks.
铅接触是个不错的诊断
Lead exposure's a nice diagnosis.
希望能成功
I hope it pays off.
肯定没问题
It will.
我很欣赏你的自信  不过她恐怕...
I appreciate your confidence, but she's not really--
我不是那意思  她可能会死
Oh, no, she could die.
但理论上说  我的诊断依旧会成功
But technically it will still pay off.
即使你的病人死了  还有别人会得到那对肺
Even if your patient dies, someone will get the lungs.
你还真是一点没变
You really haven't changed.
不过我已经不吃牛羊肉了
But I've given up red meat.
螯合治疗进行到第几轮了
What round of chelation is this?
第四轮
Fourth.
你是来检查我还是检查豪斯的
Are you checking up on me or on House?
检查这个病例
This case.
特殊情况
Unique situation.
输氧浓度
Oxygenating?
98%  气道梗阻解除
98%. Airway resistance down.
很好  豪斯还好吗
Great! Is House okay?
我不知道
I have no idea.
爸  你在这干什么
Dad, what are you doing here?
我收到你的消息了
Got your text.
给你带了你母亲做的好菜
I brought you some of your mother's goom cook.
什么消息
What text?
让我给你送晚饭的消息啊
The one asking me to bring you some dinner.
我去过神经科了
I went by neurology.
助理告诉我你休假了
The secretary said you were on leave.
我在为这个病例做会诊
I'm consulting on this case.
特殊情况
Unique situation.
看上去很复杂啊
It looks very complicated.
你能帮上忙吗
You can help with that?
肺不行了  我得进去了
Lungs are crashing. I have to go.
拜拜
Bye.
将吸入氧浓度调到100%
Increasing to 100% FiO2.
生理盐水流速下降到10毫升每秒
Saline flow is down to 10 ccs.
堵塞吗  线路中有凝块吗
Blockage? Clot in the line?
螯合治疗使它恶化了
Chelation is making it worse.
这意味着铅接触的想法是错的
It means we were wrong about lead.
别管那些了  先抢救这肺吧
Hold the analysis and help me save this thing.
生理盐水只有流入
Saline's flushing it forward
没有流出
but getting no return.
单向阀  出现血管痉挛
One-way valve. Vasospasm.
如果你是对的  钙通道阻滞剂应该能缓解这症状
If you're right, calcium channel blocker should relex the artery.
肺没有神经系统
The lungs have no nervous system.
那还会管用吗
Will that still work?
很快就能知道了
We'll know soon.
生理盐水流速上升
Saline flows rising.
血管痉挛得以缓解
Vasospasm is relexing.
左肺恢复正常
Left lung is pinking up.
干的好
Good job.
右肺中叶没有恢复正常
Right middle lobe isn't.
没反应
Nothing.
我们破坏了部分肺叶
We killed part of the lung.
请呼平托医生去介入导管室
Page Dr. Pinto stat to the cath lab.
我们要去介入导管室吗
We're going to the cath lab?
你认为有可能是
Are you thinking that maybe--
什么  谁
What? Who?
一片肺叶坏死意味着还有四片活着
One dead lobe means four alive ones.
不仅足够进行移植
It means enough to transplant
还意味着我们有部分坏死组织可以进行测试
with a side order of dead tissue that we can test.
这还说得通  不像你偷了我的手机的行为
It makes sense. Unlike you stealing my phone.
反正你发消息不花钱
You have unlimited texting.
在你父母知道之前  你永远不会明白
Until your parents know, you will never see that punch
那拳究竟意味着什么
for what it really was.
那是属于你的二月四日
Your February 4th.
斯里兰卡独立日
Sri Lankan Independence Day.
我告诉过你我是韩国和菲利宾混血
I told you I'm Korean and Filipino.
我也告诉过你我没在听
And I told you I wasn't listening.
通过肢体说明了这点
By my actions.
暴力并不是解决冲突的适当方法
Violence isn't an appropriate way to handle conflict.
那只是一时的软弱
It was a moment of weakness.
你冲我大喊  向一群
You barked at me, picked a fight
油漆工挑衅
with a painting crew.
也许是时候认清
Maybe it's time to recognize
这并非性格缺陷
it's not a character flaw.
而是你的本性使然
Maybe it's your character.
-平托  -豪斯
- Pinto! - House.
拥抱你心中那个小贱人吧
Embrace your inner bitch.
为什么螯合治疗使肺恶化了呢
So why did chelation make the lungs worse?
在平托回来前我们有五分钟时间
We got about five minutes till Pinto gets back.
-帮我一把  -不
- Give me a hand with this. - No.
我又从捐献者使用过的
I tracked down another bag of plasma
那批血浆中抽检了一袋
from the batch they used on the donor.
没有检测到其它接触物
Negative for all our other exposures.
如果是结节病
Sarcoidosis could be inflamed
应该会造成红肿发炎
by the treatment.
我是个瘸子
I am a cripple
需要帮助
in need of assistance.
移植小组查了血管紧张素转换酶
Transplant team ran an A.C.E.
-结果是阴性的  -这是我的
- Negative. - It's mine.
这也是你的工作
And it's your job.
我的工作是协助你治好这对肺
My job is to assist you in curing the lungs.
这把椅子会帮我完成这工作
This chair will help me do that.
桥上掉下来的碎屑有没有可能
What if the scrapings from the bridge
含有其它重金属  比如铍或石棉
contained other heavy metals like beryllium or asbestos.
那样针对铅进行的螯合治疗不会使肺情况恶化
Chelation for lead wouldn't have made them worse.
不过...
But...
也许重金属并非来自外部
Maybe the problem isn't a heavy metal from outside.
而是来自内部
It's inside.
它们未能按正常情况离开身体
But it's not leaving the body like it's supposed to.
而是困住了
It's stuck.
是铁
Iron.
捐赠者患有铁血黄素沉着症
The donor had hemosiderosis.
他的身体不能代谢铁元素
His body wasn't disposing of iron.
大量的铁元素停留在了肺里
Massive amounts choke up the lungs.
那我们的螯合治疗会造成严重后果
Then our chelation would wreak havoc
因为那会带去更多的金属元素
because it picks up too much stuff.
去对坏死的肺叶细胞进行铁元素染色
Go stain the dead lung tissue for iron.
实在抱歉  年轻的小姐  我明显不会帮你
I'm sorry, young lady, I simply will not help you
一起偷这把椅子
steal this chair.
-平托  -豪斯
- Pinto. - House.
你好
Hi.
她几乎没办法喘气了
She can barely catch her breath.
肺准备好了吗
Lungs ready yet?
有点耽搁
We have small set back.
我们在进行铁质过量检查
We're testing for iron overload.
我以为是铅
I thought it was lead.
这是个不确切的推断
This is not an exact process.
你的小气道系统正在崩溃
Your small airways are collapsing.
使你得不到充足的氧气
You're not getting enough oxygen.
我想试着加压
I'd like to try forcing
将富氧悬浮液打入你的肺部
an oxygen-rich slurry into your lungs.
这样会打开气道  多给你些时间
It should open up the airways and buy you some time
直到移植肺准备好
until the lungs are ready.
液体  进入我的肺部
Fluid? In my lungs?
听起来就跟溺水一样
Sounds like drowning.
没错
It is.
会疼的  不是吗
Gonna hurt, isn't it?
是的  和溺水的痛苦差不多
Yes. A fair amount.
不要
No.
我受够了
I'm done.
豪斯  护士看见你进来了
House, the nurses saw you come in.
请进
Enter.
这是厕所啊
It's a bathroom.
怪不得座位上有个洞
Ah, explains the hole in this chair.
上帝  我想死办公室的门了
God, I missed doors.
还有空气清新剂
And air freshener.
现在走吧
Now go away.
我在等化验结果
I'm waiting for some test results.
我的病人签了放弃抢救同意书  她放弃了
My patient signed a DNR. She's giving up.
看来会有其他人得到那对肺了
Looks like someone else will be getting the lungs.
好像你又说对了
Making this yet another interaction with you in which I get nothing.
你不能掌控你的病人又不是我的错
It's not my fault you can't handle your patient.
她说她受够了
She said she's done.
我花了半小时想让她回心转意
I spent half an hour trying to change her mind,
但她很坚决
but she'd made her decision.
我接受了  这叫做尊重
I accepted that. It's called respect.
那么尊重之后呢
Well, what's after respect?
你就换个方式
You find another angle.
握着她的手
You hold her hand,
让她妹妹祈求
get the sister to beg,
捂住你的耳朵
stick your fingers in your ears,
假装什么都没听到
pretend you can't hear.
你全力以赴就行
You do whatever it takes.
全力以赴
Oh, whatever it takes.
谢谢你  豪斯
Thanks, house.
我还真是没想到啊
I hadn't thought of that.
你在检测什么
What are you testing for?
血铁质
Hemosiderosis.
我在为过量的铁质染色
I'm staining for excess iron.
老实回答我
Promising.
你父亲的意外出现
When your dad showed up unexpectedly,
豪斯插手了吗
House have a hand in that?
我猜他肯定经常多管闲事
I'm guessing he does things like that a lot.
他喜欢别人就这样
His version of a compliment.
我跟芝加哥神经学权威谈过
I spoke to the head of neurology in Chicago.
给你做了个很好的推荐
I gave you a good recommendation.
你提到发生过什么了吗
Did you mention what happened?
律师不允许我说
Lawyers say I'm not allowed to.
这结果对大家都好
It works out well for everyone.
这样对你有什么好处
Why exactly is that good for you?
你说什么
Excuse me?
我是个天才内科医生  在我们班名列前茅
I'm a talented physician, top 2% of my class.
是这家医院的有利资产
I'm an asset to this hospital,
而你却想放弃我  让我去芝加哥
an asset you're about to lose to Chicago.
是你申请了那份工作
You applied for the job.
你请我打电话去推荐的你
You asked me to call and recommend you.
应该是安德鲁斯离开医院才对
Andrews is the one that should leave.
他是导师
He's the supervisor.
是他摸我在先
He touched me first.
在听证会前
I can't discuss any of that,
我无法参与讨论
not before the hearing.
但如果你对芝加哥有疑问
But if you're having doubts about Chicago,
我可以再给他们打电话
I can call them back.
不用了  谢谢你
No. Thank you.
福曼医生
Dr. Foreman?
能来看看这个吗
Would you look at this?
铁质
Iron?
不是
No.
白细胞
White blood cells.
是感染的典型症状
Classic presentation of infection.
我们怎么会遗漏了这个
How the hell did we miss that?
活检显示白细胞被浸润
Biopsy revealed white blood cell infiltrates.
原来是感染
Infection was right after all.
在监狱里  新鲜水果简直是珍馐
Fresh fruit in prison is usually chicken.
你怎么一点儿也不担心
Why aren't you more alarmed?
我们没时间了
We're running out of time.
她要死了
Aahh, she's dying!
我大叫那会你有没有想明白
Were you able to figure out what was wrong
是哪里出了问题
while I was screaming?
感染通常是移植手术
Infection was the first thing
首要处理的问题
that the transplant team treated for.
如果细菌在脏器外露时显现
Which would have worked
治疗就会起作用
if the bacteria had been out in the open.
如果他们藏在肺细胞里面呢
If they're hiding inside the lung cells...
我在想布鲁氏菌
I'm thinking brucella.
而要排除它的话  你需要特别操作
And to wipe that out, you need special ops.
一套完好的免疫系统
An intact immune system.
但白细胞不就是吗
But that's what white blood cells are.
它们是免疫系统的一部分
They're part of the immune defense force,
就像步兵团
like the infantry.
但那对肺需要空军和海军陆战队
But those lungs need the air force and the marines,
需要抗体如注
antibodies raining down from above.
抗生素和免疫球蛋白
Antibiotics and IVIG.
你对你以前的团队也用隐喻吗
Did you use metaphors for your old team?
还是你觉得我尤其白痴
Or do you just think I'm particularly stupid?
不  他们也都很白痴
No, they were stupid too.
你在这干什么
What are you doing here?
我来找温妮莎
I'm here for Vanessa.
现在不是时候  鲍比
Now is not the time, Bobby.
是她让我来的
She asked me to come.
不是吗  医生
Right, Doc?
实际上  是我的主意
Actually, it was my idea.
什么  你在想什么啊
What? What were you thinking?
她不想见他
She doesn't want to see him.
温妮莎准备放弃化疗时
When Vanessa was ready to quit chemo,
鲍比是唯一能让她
Bobby's the one
再坚持下去的人
who got her to do one more round.
没错  然后再让她酗酒
Yeah, and then he got her drunk.
至少告诉我你今天没喝酒
At least tell me you haven't been drinking today.
我该走了
I should go.
真好真好  大伙都聚齐了呀
Hail, hail, the gang's all here.
美人
Hey, beautiful.
病例尽在掌控
Case is under control.
现在是我的个人时间
It's me time.
温妮莎同意做肺灌浆了
Vanessa's gonna do the lung slurry.
你推我一把是对的
You were right to push me.
我需要有人推一把  谢谢你
I needed that. Thank you.
那你不生我气了
So we're good?
你的建议很好
It was good advice.
我只是过来谢你
Just came here to say thank you.
我喜欢你这个人
I like you.
跟你做朋友很开心
I have fun with you.
如果你能诚实地说
And, if you can honestly say
你不喜欢我这个人
that you don't like me,
跟我做朋友不开心
you don't have fun with me,
我可以接受
I can accept that.
我们快把这页揭过去
But just do whatever you have to do
怎么样随你
to get over this.
照我脸上来一拳
You can punch me in the face,
裆下踢一脚都行
kick me in the nuts.
二选一
Either/or.
两样都来我伤不起
Both seems excessive.
豪斯  问题是
The thing is, House...
我不喜欢你这个人
I don't like you.
什么时候开始变色的
When did the discoloration start?
静脉注射免疫球蛋白后几分钟
A few minutes after I started the IVIG.
说明我们关于感染的判断是错误的
Means we're wrong about infection.
没有我们  只有你
And by we, you mean you.
这对肺被你毁了
You screwed up the lungs.
不是自身免疫  不是癌症
Wrong about autoimmune, not cancer,
不是重金属
heavy metals,
不是遗传问题
genetic issues...
-升高呼气末正压值  -已经是最大值了
- Increase peep.  - Already maxed out.
我们已经走到了悬崖边缘
We're close to the point of no return.
这对肺不可能用于移植了
The lungs will never be viable for transplant.
我需要
I need...
我需要想法
I need ideas.
IgA肾病
IgA nephropathy.
已经排除了
That's already ruled out.
-狼疮  -不是
- Lupus. - No.
我们可能已经来不及了
Maybe we're just out of time.
不到最后永远不会来不及
We're out of time when we're out of time.
除非肺死或者病人死
When they die or she dies.
尽量维持稳定
Keep them stable as long as you can.
我需要思考
I need to think.
一  二
One, two...
三
Three...
许个愿  许个愿
Make a wish. Make a wish.
这对肺吸烟
The lungs are a smoker.
别人不知道你总该清楚
You of all people should know better.
那孩子从不吸烟
But the kid never smoked.
他玩牌
He played poker.
哪有牌桌上没人抽雪茄的
Who plays poker without cigars?
他不抽别人总会抽
Even if he didn't light up himself...
那是个雨天
It was a rainy night.
窗户都关着
The windows were closed.
天下父母都觉得自己的孩子与众不同
All parents think their kids are special.
他的父母倒想对了
And these ones were right.
至少他的白细胞很特殊
At least his white blood cells were special.
遇烟发生反应  并且无法停止
They had on on switch for reacting to smoke, but no off.
他吸入少量烟  会出现小毛病
When he inhaled small amounts of smoke, he had small problems.
没人注意到过
No one even noticed.
吸入大量的烟
Big amounts of smoke,
就足以毁掉一页肺
that's enough to trash a lung.
他吸入那些雪茄烟气之后
As soon as he breathed in all that cigar smoke,
就已经必死无疑
he was a dead man.
摩托车祸不过是无意义的戏剧化花边
The motorcycle accident was an unnecessary dramatic flourish.
嗜酸细胞性肺炎
Eosiniphilic pneumonitis.
可是之前用的类固醇该能治好才对
But the steroids would have treated for that.
我之前的判断是对的
I was right.
不是医学方面
Not about anything medical,
但我的比喻是完美的
but my metaphors were perfect.
我们需要更猛烈的打击
We need to hit it harder.
我们要地毯式轰炸  闪电战
We need to carpet bomb, blitzkrieg.
动用核武器
We need the nuclear option.
你下面就要说必须用放疗了  是不是
At some point you're going to say we need to radiate, right?
看吧  比喻还是有用的
See, the metaphors work.
可那会损伤健康的肺组织
But that'll destroy the good lung too.
用强效混合免疫抑制剂会更好
Better to go with a strong cocktail of immunosuppressants.
时间来不及
Won't be fast enough.
威尔森需要这对肺
Wilson needs these lungs.
见效了
It's working.
他成功了
He did it.
我不去芝加哥了
I'm not going to Chicago.
你要留下来  就得举行听证会
If you stay, we have to have a hearing.
我知道
I know.
爸爸
Dad...
现在有空吗
Do you have a minute?
胸腔清理完毕
Thoracic cavity clear.
准备接受移植肺
Ready for the donor lungs.
感谢上帝你找了他来
Thank God you called him.
不知今后会怎么样
I wonder what happens now.
她可以的
She can handle it.
豪斯
House.
有东西给你
Got something for you.
我在储藏室找到了你的东西
I found your stuff in storage.
只给你这间
This is all you get.
外间还是归整形外科
Ortho still has the outer office.
那可不好
Well, that sucks.
奇斯  陶博和十三坐哪
Where are Chase, Taub, and Thirteen gonna sit?
不用谢  豪斯
You're welcome, House.
一起吃晚饭
Dinner later?
我买东西
I'll pick something up.
听说有家素食餐厅不错
I heard about a good new vegetarian place.
鬼才要食素  我要吃牛排
Screw that. I want a steak.
晚上8点你家见
I'll meet you at your place at 8:00.